A Guide to the Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse, 1981-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse 1981-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10726-o
This collection consists of ca. 600 items (5.5 Hollinger boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Alan Cheuse of Fairfax, Virginia, placed his papers on loan to the Library on October 14, 1996. The papers were purchased by the Library on September 11, 2003.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of ca. 600 items (5.5 Hollinger boxes), [1967 ?], 1981-1996, and undated, additional papers of Alan Cheuse including personal and professional correspondence, post cards, and cards; biographical summaries; printed material; invitations to literary events and conferences; photographs; course evaluations from The Johns Hopkins University; book reviews; a 1995 appointment book; contracts; five cassette tape recordings, including two of Cheuse, Mary Lee Settle, and George Garrett reading their works, the PEN/Faulkner Award for Fiction Gala 1995 "Journeys," The Diane Rehm Show Readers' Review, and Talk of the Nation Bookclub of the Air; another typescript of the screenplay for Rabbi Guatemala A Suite of Scenes; short stories, essays, and introductions by Alan Cheuse; manuscript, proof, and other material pertaining to the work by Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco on Talking Horse Bernard Malamud on Life and Work(published 1996); short stories included in The Sound of Writing, and manuscripts of stories by other authors.
Correspondents include: Chester Aaron, (1996 Feb 21); Lee K. Abbott, (1995 Oct 23; 1996 Mar 4 and 19); Joan Acocella, (1995 Dec 13; 1996 Mar 16); John W. Aldridge, (1995 Sep 3; Dec 2); Wilton Barnhardt, (1995 Jul 21); Stephen Becker, (1994 Sep 21); Joe David Bellamy, (1995 Oct 27); Lucy Jane Bledsoe, (1995 Sep 29); J. Bloom, (1995 Oct 15); Chris Bohjalian, (1995 Apr 30); Kurt Brown, (1995 Nov 17); Jackson R Bryer,. (1995 Jul 27; 1996 Feb 29); Emilie Buchwald, (re Rowing in Eden 1995 Dec 3, 13) and (1996 Mar 22; Apr 29); Robert Olen Butler, (1995 Sep 19); Fred D. Chappell, (1995 Apr 3 re ending to The Encyclopedia Daniel); Richard H. Costa, (1995 Jan 24; Apr 24); Deborah Cummins, (1995 Sep 29); J. Madison Davis, (1995 Jun 13); Susan Dodd, (1996 Apr 4); Stuart Dybek, (1995 Apr 17); Richard Elman, (1994 Dec 10; 1995 Jan 18; May 15; Jun 21); Brian Evenson, (1995 May 30); David M. Fine, (1995 Jun 8; Aug 12); Maria Flook, (1995 Apr 26; Dec 19); Richard Ford, (1995 May 31; Dec 6); Russell Fraser, (1995 Sep 26; Oct 12); George Garrett, (1995 Apr 28; Jul 20); Jim Glickman, (1996 May 29); Herbert Gold, (1995 May 19); Stephanie Gunning, re Rowing Into Eden(1996 Jun 22); Stephen Heinemann, (1996 Jun 7); Jim [Houston], (1996 Mar 17); Dallas Hudgens, (1996 Jan 10); Brian Kiteley, (1996 May 9); Jim Landis, (1995 Jul 11); Kathryn Lang, (re Rowing Into Eden 1994 Sep 12; and 1995 Jun 20); Margot Livesey, (1996 Mar 3); Reginald McKnight, (1995 May 22); Charlotte Painter, (1995 Sep 14); Daniel J. Peters, (1995 May 17); Robert Pinsky, (1996 Jun 1); Roxana Robinson, (1994 Nov 13); George A. Singer, (1995 Apr 6; May 15); Les Standiford, (1994 Aug 31; Dec 16; 1995 Oct 30; 1996 Jan 26); Marion Stegner, (1995 May 24); Robert Sward, (n.d.); Keith Taylor, (n.d.); David Weimer, (1995 Dec 9); Jon Manchip White, (1995 Nov 3; Dec 24); Allen Wier, (1996 Jun 6); C.K. Williams, (1996 Jan 2); Terry Tempest Williams, (1995 Jul 9); Geoffrey Wolff, (1995 Oct 17); Al Young, (1995 Sep 6)
Contents List
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE and MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
  - Appointment Book 1995 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Summaries 1995 (Box 1)
  - Cards and Post Cards (2 folders) 1994-1996, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (7 folders) 1994-1995 Oct (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (4 folders) 1995 Nov-1996 Jun, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - Nicholas Delbanco and Talking Horse Bernard Malamud on Life and Work 1992-1996 (Box 2)
  - Course Evaluations 1995 (Box 2)
  - Course Syllabus and Outline - Inside the Novel English 660 1996 Spring (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers 1990-1996 (Box 2)
  - Photographs 1992, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Printed Material 1994-1996 (Box 2)
  - Printed Material re PEN/Faulkner Award, Pegasus Prize For Literature and Guggenheim Fellowships 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Printed Material re Writers' Conferences, Lecture Series, and Workshops 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Short Story Lists for Forthcoming Books ca. 1996 (Box 2)
- SERIES II: PAPERS RE TALKING HORSE BERNARD MALAMUD ON LIFE AND WORK
  - Bernard Malamud Conference, Oregon State University 1996 May (Box 3)
  - Descriptions and Notes re the Bernard Malamud Manuscript Collection at the Library of Congress ca. 1993-1995, n.d. (Box 3)
  - "How Malamud Did It" by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco, with corrections and changes n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "The Magic Barrel" by Bernard Malamud 1996 Nov 16, TMs and proof (Box 3)
  - "Malamud At Play And Work" by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco in New York Times Book Review 1996 Feb 13 and Mar 17, TMs (Box 3)
  - "On Bernard Malamud" in AWP Chronicle by Nicholas Delbanco 1995 May 15, TMs (Box 3)
  - "Remembering Malamud -- And His Art" by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - Talking Horse Bernard Malamud on Life and Work edited by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco (Early Draft) ca. 1995, TMs (Box 3)
  - Talking Horse Bernard Malamud on Life and Work edited by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco ca. 1996, TMs (Box 3)
  - Talking Horse Bernard Malamud on Life and Work edited by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco, signed by Cheuse ca. 1996, Uncorrected proof (Box 3)
  - Talking Horse Bernard Malamud on Life and Work edited by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco - Promotion and Publicity 1996 (Box 3)
  - "Talking Horse: Remembering Bernard Malamud" by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco with changes and corrections ca. 1995, TMs (Box 3)
  - "Talking Horse: Remembering Bernard Malamud" by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco in Atlantic Monthly 1995 Jun 28, TMs (Box 3)
  - "Talking Horse: Remembering Bernard Malamud" by Alan Cheuse and Nicholas Delbanco in Atlantic Monthly(Uncorrected Author's Proof) 1995 Nov 29, galleys (Box 3)
- SERIES III: MANUSCRIPTS
  - "Accident" in Sandlapper 1981 Mar, print (Box 4)
  - "Apache Woods" n.d., TMs (Box 4)
  - "An Appetite As Great As Any Other" n.d., TMs (Box 4)
  - "Biography of an Unknown Woman" n.d., TMs (Box 4)
  - Book Reviews A-Z, by title (3 folders) 1995-1996, TMs and print (Box 4)
  - "The Distinction Between Twilight and Crepuscule" Drafts 1-4 [1996 Feb], 5 TMs (Box 4)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Yearbook- "American Literature, 1995" 1995, TMs (Box 4)
  - Essays n.d. (Box 4)
  - "The Eye Alone (Part One)" in The Texas Review 1996, 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Fitzgerald's Christmas Carol, or the Burden of The Camel's Back" with corrections and changes by the editor n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Flutter" ca. 1996, TMs (Box 4)
  - "Garden of the Gods" in BWR [1967?], print (Box 4)
  - "The Historical Novel in Literature and Society - Introduction" 1995 May 15, TMs (Box 4)
  - Introduction of Madison Bell and Edwidge Danticat at Haiti Night PEN/Faulkner n.d., TMs (Box 4)
  - Introduction of Stuart Dybek n.d., TMs (Box 4)
  - "The Light on Alan Cheuse: A Dialogue" An Interview with Alan Cheuse by Neila C. Seshachari in Weber Studies 1990, proofs (Box 4)
  - Manuscripts and Literary Work by Other Authors, including George Garrett and Rudolfo Anaya 1993-1996, n.d. (Box 4)
  - "The Mexican Maid" with corrections [1994 May 11], TMs (Box 4)
  - "The Mexican Maid" with corrections, published in The Antioch Review 1995, TMs (Box 4)
  - "Midnight Ride" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 5)
  - "Midnight Ride" Old Version n.d., 2 TMs (Box 5)
  - "Midnight Ride," with corrections by Richard Ford 1996, 3 TMs (Box 5)
  - "Midnight Ride" Fifth Draft n.d., TMs (Box 5)
  - "Nights on the Cumberland Plateau" in The Texas Review 1988 Spring, TMs (EC) (Box 5)
  - "On the Beach" n.d., TMs (EC) (Box 5)
  - "On the Millstone River," with corrections [1995 Oct], 2 TMs (Box 5)
  - "On the Tram in Bennington Review 1985, galleys (Box 5)
  - "The Pac-Man Murders" in Blue Ox Review 1985 Winter, print (Box 5)
  - "The Plan" published in That's What I Like About the South 1991, TMs (Box 5)
  - Rabbi Guatemala A Suite of Scenes (Adapted from the novel The Grandmothers' Club by Alan Cheuse), with corrections n.d., TMs (Box 5)
  - "The Seals" in New Letters 1987, print (Box 5)
  - "Slides" n.d., TMs (EC) (Box 5)
  - Sound of Writing Short Stories Series 14 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Sound of Writing Short Stories - Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1996, n.d. (Box 5)
  - "The State of the Story" in The Literary Review edited by Alan Cheuse and James Thomas with an Introduction by Nat Sobel [1994] (Box 5)
  - "Tall-Grass Prairie," with corrections 1996, TMs (Box 6)
  - "Toward Easter Island" n.d., print (Box 6)
  - "The Tunnel" with corrections 1996, 3 TMs (Box 6)
  - Alan Cheuse, George Garrett, and Mary Lee Settle reading for the [Virginia Foundation for the Humanities ?], Richmond, Virginia 1994 Oct 15, audio cassette tape recording (Box 6)
  - Alan Cheuse and George Garrett reading at Weber State 1995 Apr 20 and 21, audio cassette tape recording (Box 6)
  - Talk of the Nation BookClub of the Air "Crossing to Safety" on National Public Radio 1995 Jan 29, audio cassette tape recording (Box 6)
  - PEN/Faulkner Award for Fiction Gala 1995 "Journeys" 1995, audio cassette tape recording (Box 6)
  - The Diane Rehm Show Readers' Review at The American University, Washington, D.C. 1996 Jan 19, audio cassette tape recording (Box 6)